# **Daniel Zhang**

jmit.modern@gmail.com

IT Professional with 7+ years of experience in developing web and business intelligence solutions for diverse industry clients. Highly instrumental in all phases of the SDLC, with expertise in algorithms and data structures. Successful in developing bespoke solutions, optimizing business procedures, processes, and productivity.

#### TECHNOLOGY

Programming: Ruby, Python, Node.js, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX

Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Django, Flask, Express, Nest.js, Laravel

Frontend: React.js, Vue.js, Angular.js, Javascript, Typescript

DBMS: MySQL, Postgres, SQL Server, MongoDB

CI/CD: Git, GitHub, Gitlab

Cloud: AWS (EC2, S3, Lamda), GCP, Heroku

Systems: Linux/Apache, Windows Server/IIS, Docker

Project Management: Slack, JIRA Administration

Processes: Agile, Scrum, Requirements, Design, Development, Database

Administration, Testing, Deployment, Maintenance, Documentation, ETL

Process, Content Management Systems

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **SOFRTWARE ENGINEER**

Engu Inc, February 2021 - Jan 2022

- Developed web-based event space rental service with React.js, Typescript, and Ruby on Rails
- Developed user experience and implemented front-ends serving numerous personas (Space Owner, Expert, User, Administrator)
- Integrated payment gateway services to receive and distribute payment to Space Owners and Experts for space rentals

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Huineng Science and Techology Co, Ltd, Dec 2019 – Jan 2021

- Experience with multiple blockchain technologies (Ethereum/Polygon/BSC/Solana/Avalanche).
- Deployed 20+ smart contracts in Ethereum, designed and developed 8+ DApps using web3.js, react.js, ethers.js.
- Developed cryptocurrency exchange platform based on Coinbase, Kraken, Binance, Stabletown.

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Izwx, Inc, Sep 2017 - Nov 2019

- Renewed and maintained Vue.js frontend, PHP, Laravel backend Ecommerce platform, warehouse management system
- Built the RESTful APIs and reusable services, modules in PHP, Laravel
- Integrated the APIs in Vue.js frontend and Configured Webpack to bundle code using Vue.js, Vuex, SCSS, Babel, and implemented hot module reloading.
- Deployed in AWS EC2
- Increased customer satisfaction scores by 12%

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

*Councilbox*, Jun 2015 – Aug 2017

- Built and maintained React.js Frontend, PHP, Laravel backend the Video Streaming Lecturing System
- Built the RESTful APIs, reusable services and modules in PHP, Laravel
- Built the components and templates, pages in ATOMIC design patterns in React.js
- Integrated the WebRTC service API and websocket streaming API

## **EDUCATION**

## **Beijing Jiaotong University**

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Engineering, March 2014